Prologue: Reunion

Rio arrived at the Galarc Castle with Christina and Flora. Using his position as Honorary Knight, he smoothly bypassed all the necessary procedures to be shown to King Francois in a drawing room, its use restricted to royalty.

Apart from Rio, Christina, and Flora, those present in the room were Satsuki, Second Princess Charlotte, and everyone who attended the earlier marriage interview (Liselotte and her parents, Duke and Duchess Cretia; King Francois; and Duke Huguenot, Roanna, and Hiroaki, the representatives from the Restoration).

Incidentally, the first to come running after Rio brought Christina and Flora to the castle were Roanna and Duke Huguenot. Hiroaki hadn’t moved as quickly, in contrast to them, and had joined up with them belatedly before they all made their way to this room.

Once everyone seated themselves, King Francois turned to Rio with a near exasperated look. “You truly exceed my expectations, Haruto.”

The others in the room all had similar expressions.

“I sincerely apologize for creating a commotion...” Rio replied with a look of shame.

“It’s a compliment. You’ve surpassed my expectations so much that the first feeling that comes to me about you is astonishment,” Francois said with a cheery grin.

“It is exactly as I said before, no? I was certain that Sir Haruto would add to his list of distinguished services before long,” Charlotte said proudly, a look of delight spreading across her whole face.

Francois chuckled in response. “I was surprised back when I heard you returned from the airship with Lady Miharu by flight, but this incident has surpassed that. At any rate, it is wonderful news for both the Restoration and the Galarc Kingdom that Princess Christina and Princess Flora are alive. I should have prioritized my commendation before my surprise. Well done. This is truly a tremendous feat.”

As he thanked Rio, Francois directed his gaze towards Christina and Flora, who were seated to Rio’s right, before moving on to look at the section of the drawing room occupied by the representatives of the Restoration—Duke Huguenot, Roanna, and Hiroaki—in turn.

“The Restoration is extremely thankful for Haruto’s deeds as well.” Duke Huguenot bowed his head deeply and briefly expressed his strong feelings of gratitude. He must have been truly relieved, letting out an audible sigh.

“I’m so glad you’re safe. Truly... so glad...” Roanna had tears in her eyes as she looked at Christina and Flora. Seated beside her was Hiroaki, who congratulated the two on their survival, albeit in a slightly sullen voice.

“It’s great that you’re alive.”

His biggest crush had just rejected him, so his mind was in a complicated state. Liselotte was also in the room, but he seemed to be intentionally keeping her out of his field of vision. However, the fact he had returned to the room at all meant he felt either curiosity or concern about what happened to Christina and Flora.

“Thank you for worrying about us. We were able to return safely thanks to Sir Haruto, as you can see,” Flora replied to Hiroaki and the rest of the Restoration with a gentle expression.

When Haruto’s name came up, Hiroaki snorted with an annoyed look.

“Please tell us what happened, from the beginning to the end. How did you two go missing in the first place? How did Haruto get involved in all this?” Francois asked, looking at Rio and the princesses.

Christina exchanged a look with Rio and sighed heavily. “Based on what you’re saying, it sounds like the message from Rubia didn’t arrive after all.”

Francois looked puzzled. “What...?”

“I will explain everything that happened to Flora and myself. It’ll be a long story, so please let me finish speaking before asking any questions.”

With that preamble, Christina began to explain what happened.

Chapter 3: To Rodania

Rio bid a temporary farewell to Satsuki, Charlotte, and Liselotte and boarded the Restoration’s airship for Rodania. After boarding, he was invited to the living room where Christina and Flora were staying to wait for their arrival. Duke Huguenot had been excluded from Christina’s invitation, so he was waiting in another room.

“Thank you for the invitation,” Rio said to the sisters as soon as he sat down. Given how the three of them had traveled to the Galarc Kingdom’s capital together, it felt a little strange.

“It’s become natural for the three of us to be together lately, so it does feel a little odd. Only one day has passed since we arrived in the capital, but it feels like it’s been a long time since we last saw each other.”

“I was just thinking the same, Christina.”

Apparently, Christina and Flora felt the same way as Rio. If there was anything that had changed between them, then that would be it.

“While we were traveling, the only time the artifact didn’t change my hair color was when it was just the three of us in the house. Those were the times I could relax, but I cannot do that here. Perhaps that may be why.”

Rio pointed out the difference between when he was alert and not. In other words, when the three of them traveled together, Rio interacted with Christina and Flora using his relaxed side more, but now he was here as Haruto Amakawa, his alert side instead.

“Indeed, we’ve also become more tense since rejoining the organization.”

“I see...”

Christina and Flora agreed with him.

“Actually, there were several things I wanted to discuss before arriving in Rodania, which is why I called you here. You may not be able to unwind while you’re here, but would you be willing to hear me out for a while?”

“Of course. I’d be glad to.”

“Then I’ll start with the easiest topics. If you’re going to bring Miharu and your friends to the Galarc Kingdom, does that mean Sara and the others are in Rodania right now? I’m greatly indebted to Sara’s group, so I’d love to thank them again if possible.”

For her first topic, Christina brought up the location of Sara and the others.

“I have another stone house that I use for my travels. They’ve been using that to live quietly in the forest outskirts of Rodania.”

“I see.”

“I know where they’re located, so it’s possible for them to come to Rodania within a day or so. But like I’ve mentioned before, Sara and the others are young ladies from a minority group, and they’ve been taught to avoid kingdom politics. I believe they’d want to avoid attending anything with a political nuance, so if you could keep that in mind as you interact with them, it may be possible to arrange a meeting. I apologize for having so many requirements...”

Rio bowed his head. He wanted to leave the matter of whether they attended or not to the people in question, so he gave requirements even though he was speaking to two princesses.

“I understand. In that case, if Sara and the others visit Galarc with you, I’ll either find some time to visit your mansion or set aside some time to speak to them on the airship there. Would that be all right?” Christina suggested.

“Of course, I don’t mind, but... Is it okay to bother two princesses like this?”

Although he was the one who set the conditions, Rio felt slightly flustered by the thought of making two princesses visit him. In reality, it was very rare for royalty to go out of their way to visit the mansions of nobility.

“Yes. I wish to tell them thank you, so it’s only polite for me to visit them. With the mansion belonging to you, there won’t be a problem if we go using this pretense. If they visit you while in Rodania, I can arrange it so that no one from the Restoration will approach your estate during their stay,” Christina stated clearly.

“Thank you very much for the consideration. Then I will contact you if Sara and the others decide to come.”

Rio bowed his head respectfully.

“Please do. Then next is the topic of Professor Celia.”

Christina brought up Celia’s name somewhat reluctantly.

“Is something the matter with the professor?”

Rio had been unable to refer to Celia with her title in front of others lately and often referred to her only by name, but since there was no need to do so in front of the royal siblings, who now knew his identity, he followed Christina’s lead and called her “professor” again.

“I believe you should inform Professor Celia that we are aware of your identity now. What do you think about this?”

“Indeed, it may be difficult to interact without sharing that information,” Rio agreed with a strained smile. “If you can arrange a setting without any other third parties, we can discuss it all together. But if that seems difficult, I can also inform her myself. I don’t mind if the three of you discuss things among yourselves afterwards,” he suggested.

“In that case, I will try to arrange a meeting for just the four of us after we arrive in Rodania, but if that doesn’t seem possible, we’ll leave the explanation to you, Sir Amakawa,” Christina said, figuring it would be better for Rio to be present at the explanation.

“Understood.” Rio nodded, seeing no problem with that.

“On top of that, I’d like to discuss the reward from the Restoration to you for the incident this time.”

Christina had been sitting elegantly to begin with, but she straightened her back even more as she brought up the topic of the reward. Then, sensing Christina’s nerves, Rio spoke up.

“Yes. I’d prefer if you could decide on something modest, if possible. I don’t wish to be a burden on you either, and there’s nothing in particular I desire anyway,” Rio stated with a frown.

“I appreciate the sentiment, but I’m afraid the circumstances are rather unavoidable.”

“Are you referring to what King Francois referred to as setting an example for others?”

“That is part of it, but the reward that was suggested for the Restoration to give to you is a betrothal to a prominent noblewoman of the organization.” Christina sighed tiredly.

“A betrothal, you say...”

Indeed, that was a rather troubling reward. Extremely troubling—that was Rio’s first thought.

“I suppose it would only be seen as a nuisance, after all?”

Christina sighed further, noticing the faint change in expression on Rio’s face.

“While I’m terribly honored to receive such an offer...”

“My apologies. I knew it would be a bother, but I had to at least mention it or things would get more troublesome in the future,” Christina said, bowing her head. She had to establish the fact she brought up the topic or she’d be hounded about it forever.

“No, it’s not something Your Highness has to apologize for... I just didn’t imagine such an offer would be made.”

“That just shows how appealing your achievements were. At present, Duke Huguenot is quite insistent on this.”

“Do you mean he wants a betrothal to a noblewoman of the Huguenot house? I didn’t know there was one available...”

“He said he wanted to offer you his eldest daughter with his second wife, I believe. However, even I recognize this is impossible considering the things his son did to you, so I can find a reason to dismiss the idea,” Christina stated clearly.

“I don’t believe the daughter is at fault, but I’d be grateful if you did so.”

“Understood. He should back down if I tell him you weren’t interested when I brought up the topic of marriage. However, Duke Huguenot isn’t the type to give up quietly. I can easily imagine him waiting for another chance to pressure you into a betrothal.”

“I see...”

“Also, regardless of rewards, you may find yourself receiving more marriage offers. While I’d love to be able to suppress them all for you, I’m afraid my current influence won’t be sufficient for that... And so, I was hoping to prepare an excuse you can use to hold the nobles at bay. Perhaps we could discuss that in further detail now.”

“What kind of excuse would be effective, specifically?”

“To be absolutely blunt, the most effective way to block all mention of marriage is to have another marriage lined up,” Christina said with a pained look.

“It certainly makes logical sense,” Rio agreed with a wry smile.

“For example, if you’ve already decided upon a first wife, anyone aiming for that position will naturally eliminate themselves. Although that wouldn’t have an effect on anyone who doesn’t care about positions.”

“If I may ask... Will it be expected of me to have multiple wives like the nobility?”

“It’s common for high-ranking nobles to have multiple wives. Your position as a noble is extremely unique, but considering your achievements, I believe many will want you to do the same,” Christina speculated in response to Rio’s troubled question.

“They’ll want me to do so... But will it still be possible for me to remain faithful to one wife if I so desire?” Rio asked, inquiring if the opposite interpretation of what she said would apply.

“Yes. The greatest reason why noble families have multiple wives is to keep the key positions they manage within their own bloodline. Those who don’t mind leaving important positions to branch families or trusted retainers marry only once, but they’re in the minority. It’s common for multiple wives to be demanded of them later, and they end up unable to refuse...” Christina explained regarding the polygamy system.

The head house was where the head of the family shouldered the finances, while branch families were separate houses that made their living independently of the head house. Generally, branch families were created when nobles married wives who couldn’t give heirs to the family. In cases where one left the head house by marrying into another, no branch family was formed.

There was also a polygamy system to make sure there would always be an heir to the family, but if one was willing to bring someone from the branch family in as an heir, then there was no need for multiple wives either. There weren’t many nobles willing to think this way, however.

“I see... I’ve learned much today. Thank you very much,” Rio said to her in awe.

“Based on this conversation, it sounds like you are opposed to having multiple wives?”

“Yes, to be honest...” Rio nodded, fairly unenthusiastically.

“Umm... I apologize for asking out of the blue, but is that because you have a specific person in mind already?”

“A specific person, huh...? I wonder...”

“I’m sorry, that was rude of me to ask. You don’t have to answer if you don’t want to,” Christina apologized quickly.

“No, that’s not what I meant... I’m just unable to think about love and marriage at this time.” Rio looked troubled, contemplating for a long moment before revealing his thoughts with a frown. However, his tone wasn’t entirely negative. “But if I had a little... just a little bit more confidence in myself... I think I’d be able to consider things positively then.”

He expressed his thoughts regarding marriage with a faint smile. He might have accomplished his revenge, but he wasn’t able to immediately switch over to the idea of marriage and happiness so easily. There was still a part of him that looked down on himself. But at the same time, he potentially felt a vague hopefulness too.

Christina and Flora stared at Rio’s expression like they were being sucked into it.

“I... see...” Christina replied awkwardly after a moment.

“The mood’s become weird because of me. I’m sorry.” Rio bowed his head with a strained smile.

Christina shook her head in a hurry. “No, I’m sorry for asking you something so improper.”

◇　◇　◇

Several hours later, the enchanted airship they were boarded on finally arrived at Rodania. Notice of Christina and Flora’s return had been sent in advance via another airship, so the harbor by Rodania’s lake was packed with the nobles of the Restoration.

When Rio and Duke Huguenot disembarked with Christina and Flora, Marquess Rodan and the other nobles approached to express their joy over their safe return. Then, as they couldn’t just stand around to talk, they boarded a carriage to the fortress that was being used as the consulate.

She doesn’t seem to be in the crowd... Aishia would’ve noticed my approach, so perhaps she’s in the middle of a class. It’s still bright, after all.

Rio swept his gaze across the crowd from inside the horse carriage, but he couldn’t see Celia anywhere. Just as he considered that, a telepathic message from Aishia arrived.

Welcome back, Haruto.

Hi, Aishia. Rio smiled reflexively as he replied in his head. The sound of Aishia’s voice was very reassuring for some reason.

Celia’s in the middle of class. She really wants to see you and the princesses, but she couldn’t cancel the lecture. She’s very frustrated.

Aha ha, I see. We’re heading for the consulate right now, and we’ll be waiting for her to finish class.

Celia’s lectures were also held in the consulate, so it was perfect.

Got it. I’ll let Celia know.

Let’s exchange some information while we’re waiting, Rio proposed as he rode in the extravagant carriage with Christina, Flora, Duke Huguenot, and Marquess Rodan.

Sure. A few incidents occurred in Rodania while you were gone. I’ll tell you about them.

That’s exactly what I was going to ask about. When I was in the Galarc Kingdom, I heard that Professor Celia spotted Reiss in Rodania.

She didn’t report every detail to the Restoration. I’ll explain what happened.

Please, Rio replied with a grim look.

“Is something the matter, Sir Amakawa?”

Across from Rio’s seat, Christina noticed the change in his expression. She looked at him with worry.

“No, it’s nothing.” Rio brushed her off with a smile and listened to Aishia’s report.

Tell me the details while we’re moving.

Chapter 5: Information Exchange

The group left the lecture hall and moved to a meeting room within the consulate. Christina and Flora sat on one side of a table with Rio and Celia sitting opposite them.

“So, I’ve invited the professor to talk with us because there’s a very important matter to discuss...” Christina said solemnly, glancing at Rio’s expression. Rio gave a small nod, which Flora watched with bated breath.

“And what matter is that...?” Celia straightened her posture. She sensed the heavy atmosphere from the faces of everyone present.

“The matter involves me and you, Professor. Can you guess what it is?” Rio joined the conversation by purposely calling her “Professor” while in front of Christina and Flora.

“Huh? Could it be...” Celia was terribly shaken. She seemed to suspect his intentions immediately but didn’t speak further out of fear of saying something carelessly.

“Princess Christina and Princess Flora are aware that I am Rio,” Rio revealed boldly, showing no panic whatsoever.

“R... Really? How... How am I supposed to react to that?”

In contrast, Celia was the one who reacted with anxiety. She still didn’t know what events had led to Rio’s identity being revealed, or what the fallout of knowing his identity was, so she nervously waited to hear if the story took a bad turn.

“Although we’ve learned that Sir Amakawa’s identity is that boy from back then... That is, the boy named Rio, we don’t plan on doing anything in particular about it. We are the only three in the Restoration that know this secret. And I fully intend on taking it with me to the grave.”

“Yes, we definitely won’t tell anyone about Sir Rio!”

Christina and Flora both spoke resolutely.

“You two...” Seeing their attitudes, Celia sighed in relief.

“We believed it would be better to exchange information with you, so we arranged this meeting to have a discussion,” Rio said.

“You could say that goal has been achieved already,” Christina commented with a hint of joy.

“Indeed. However, if you have any questions or doubts, we can use this chance to clarify things,” Rio stated, looking around at their faces.

“Questions... When you put it that way, a couple do come to mind... But everything’s been so shocking and nerve racking and relieving that they’ve all blown away.” Celia laughed, looking at Rio with a tired face. She’d had to process the situation repeatedly in a short period of time, so that was understandable.

“But if I were to describe my state of mind right now... I find it rather fresh. The fact that Princess Christina is saying Rio’s name, the fact that the three of you who were never together at the academy are together like this now, and the fact that I happen to be present to witness it...” Celia added, her expression softening.

Flora agreed with an intense nod. “It certainly is strange hearing Sir Rio’s name come from my sister’s mouth. She made absolutely sure to distance herself from him at the academy, never exchanging words with him—not even mentioning his name when he wasn’t there.”

“That— That was because I was still immature and believed I had to distance myself from him on account of our statuses...” Christina mumbled with a rare blush.

“You did call Rio ‘the boy from back then’ just now. Even though he’s right here.” Celia giggled. Even uttering Rio’s name must have been embarrassing for Christina.

“I wasn’t sure how else to refer to him...”

Christina ducked her head, blushing harder. “Sir Rio” sounded a little strange, just “Rio” wouldn’t do, and “Mister Rio” was also odd. She didn’t know how else she could call him, so she’d chosen “the boy from back then” just to be safe.

“I’ve always called him ‘Sir Rio’! But I guess I can no longer do that now...”

Even though that was what was the most comfortable for me, Flora’s expression said.

“No matter how much I tried to stop her in the past, she always worried about him.” Christina recalled the past with a sentimental look.

“That’s because saving me inconvenienced Sir Rio so much...” Flora hung her head gloomily.

“It wasn’t your fault. I was merely too much of a heretical existence within the society of that academy.”

“That... That was because of our flaws. If you hadn’t saved me, you wouldn’t have had to enter the academy, and be falsely accused of a crime at the outdoor drill... Even though Sir Rio saved me, I was helpless and unable to do anything...”

Rio acted like there was no need to worry about it, but Flora still brooded over it, gradually placing more and more of the blame on herself.

“But if I hadn’t entered the academy, I wouldn’t have met Professor Celia. That would be a problem for me,” Rio said with a teasing chuckle.

“Wha...?!” Taken aback by Rio’s sudden statement, Celia blushed.

“You two were close back then too.” Christina observed their expressions.

“I tried to keep that quiet to avoid the attention of students who didn’t think highly of him... How did you notice? I even made sure we always met up in my research lab instead of anywhere else,” Celia said.

“I never saw the two of you speaking closely in front of other students, but I sometimes caught sight of you together after class.”

“I see...”

It was precisely because Christina had been so conscious of avoiding Rio that she naturally ended up looking at him more often. Celia realized that but swallowed her words, figuring Christina would be embarrassed by having that brought up.

“Now that I think back on it, Christina must have been observing Sir Rio as well.” Flora pointed it out instead.

“...You were always watching him, so I had no choice but to notice that,” Christina said a little bluntly, probably to hide her shyness.

“But... It’s true that Sir Amakawa was an eye-catching presence back then. He absorbed knowledge at a rapid rate for an orphan, studying diligently to close the gap with the nobles of the academy in only a short amount of time—and surpassing them. Now his sword abilities even surpass Alfred, the strongest in the kingdom. In reality, I could clearly sense your latent but prominent talent back then,” Christina admitted, explaining why Rio had caught her interest at the same time.

“Surely that is an exaggeration...”

“It’s the truth. You stood out so much that it made me ashamed of how pleased I had been when I was praised as a child prodigy. You excelled far too much. However, when I learned of your true identity, everything suddenly made sense. That is, I’m not sure if this is appropriate to ask, but...”

“What is it?” Rio tilted his head, prompting her to continue.

“Lucius said... your mother was royalty...” Christina brought up the topic of Rio’s mother, Ayame.

After a long pause, Celia reacted in shock. “Huh?!”

“Huh...?” Christina was also confused.

“I actually haven’t told Celia that my mother was royalty.” Rio scratched at his cheek awkwardly as he explained the reason for Celia’s surprised reaction.

“R-Really?! Please accept my apologies!” Christina realized she’d slipped up and apologized in a panic.

“No... Now that I think about it, Lucius mentioned that during our battle, didn’t he? I didn’t forbid you from speaking about it, and there’s no problem if Celia finds out, so don’t worry about it. I don’t believe it’s a topic that needs to be told to others. Or rather, it’s difficult to speak about, so I kept it a secret until now. But this may be a good chance,” Rio said, calming Christina down without showing any particular anger.

“Then, is it true...?”

At Christina’s words, Flora and Celia’s gazes fixed on Rio.

“Yes. My mother was royalty from another kingdom,” Rio confirmed clearly.

“Th-That’s quite shocking. So your mother was a princess like Princess Christina and Princess Flora, right...?” Celia asked nervously.

“Apparently so.”

“Apparently so... That’s a tremendous thing, though... Doesn’t that make you royalty as well, Rio?” Celia’s face twitched.

“When you put it that way, I suppose so... But I only learned the truth after leaving the Beltrum Kingdom myself, a mere one or two years ago. The fact that my mother was an immigrant and that I lived in the slums makes things a little complicated. I don’t consider myself royalty either.”

So please don’t worry about it, Rio thought, trying to brush it off lightly.

“Even if you don’t think that way, it isn’t such a simple matter. Suppose you are royalty from a kingdom that has interacted with the Beltrum Kingdom before. The things Beltrum did in the past is enough cause for an international problem. Of course, your status as a royal doesn’t change the fact that our actions were unforgivable.”

The position of royalty in relations between kingdoms had a special value, which was what Christina had pointed out with a stiff expression.

“My mother was born in the Karasuki Kingdom, which is located in the Yagumo region. They have absolutely no relation to the Beltrum Kingdom, so you may rest assured.”

“Even so... The fact you learned of this one or two years ago means you met your royal relatives in your mother’s homeland, right?” Christina asked. In other words, could Rio reclaim his royal position whenever he wanted?

“I met my grandparents—the king and queen. But as I said before, the circumstances are complex, and I will never, ever be treated as royalty by my mother’s homeland.”

“Is that... Is that something I may ask about in detail?” Christina asked hesitantly.

Rio thought for a moment before answering. “It’s a highly confidential secret in the Karasuki Kingdom. Only the king, queen, and select others are aware of it. But there’s practically no interaction between the Strahl and Yagumo regions, so I don’t mind telling you if you keep it to yourselves. Though it may be a long story...”

“We swear we’ll never tell anyone else,” Christina declared with a severe look. Flora and Celia also nodded their quiet agreements.

“I understand. Now, where should I start...”

With that preface, Rio began telling them about his parents’ past.

◇　◇　◇

Before Rio spoke about his parents, he summarized what had happened between him leaving the Beltrum Kingdom and arriving at the Yagumo region. He believed that clarifying this would make things easier to understand.

After the outdoor drill four years ago, he’d left the Beltrum Kingdom to head for his parents’ homeland in the Yagumo region. He’d arrived there safely, but he had some trouble finding their exact village and had to move from town to town, until finally, he was able to meet a relative from his father’s side.

He’d stayed with his grandmother and cousin in the village his father Zen grew up in, where he learned his father was born as a farmer.

One day, the warrior named Gouki, a former acquaintance of his parents who had once served his mother Ayame, visited the village. His father, who was blessed with military talent, made a name for himself through war and had been promoted to guarding Ayame along with Gouki.

Ayame was smitten with Zen, but their love was a forbidden dream. One day, to negotiate peace with their enemy nation, a prince came to the Karasuki Kingdom, but that had been a trap. The prince’s close aide had nearly kidnapped Ayame, and Zen prevented the attempt. However, the enemy prince claimed that Zen killing his aide was an international problem, demanding that Ayame be given to him and Zen executed as reparations.

The peace had been ruined in an instant, causing the noble and military houses of the Karasuki Kingdom—as well as the citizens—to explode in fury, crying for Zen and Ayame to be handed over to the enemy as demanded.

At that time, the only option left was to allow Zen and Ayame to run away and redirect the discontent onto them, resuming the war to resolve things. With that, the Karasuki Kingdom set out for war once again, this time emerging victorious. However, there was no way to take back the fact that Zen and Ayame had fled. The two were treated as great criminals and left the kingdom, heading towards the Strahl region in search of repose.

“That’s the gist of things... You can pretty much imagine the rest. My parents threw aside their status and married in Beltrum, where I was born. After that, my father was killed by Lucius before I was old enough to remember him, and my mother was killed several years later, leaving me alone in the slums. That’s where I met all of you, on that day Princess Flora was kidnapped and you were all searching for her,” Rio concluded, wrapping up his long story.

“W-Wah...”

Celia and Flora were crying loudly.

“Umm... Hello?” Rio called out to them with a troubled look.

“That’s awful... Why... Why did such a thing...” Flora protested in tears, wiping at her eyes with a handkerchief.

Celia had her hand pressed over her mouth, completely speechless.

“I appreciate the fact you’re crying for my parents, but this happened over twenty years ago,” Rio said awkwardly.

So please don’t cry so much, he thought.

“Th-That’s wrong!”

Celia shot up from the sofa to protest fiercely.

“Wh-What is?”

What exactly was wrong? Rio tilted his head with a puzzled voice.

“I’m crying about your parents, but also about you!” Celia asserted.

“I-I see... But you already knew parts of the story already, no? How I came to live in the slums and stuff.”

He’d mentioned it in front of Christina and Flora before too.

“That’s true, but I didn’t know all of it! There were just so many sorrowful events that led to you living in the slums by yourself—like your parents’ tragic past—and you were so helpless to it all. I’m so upset! I was just living happily without a care back then...” Celia protested in tears, a tormented look on her face.

“Thank you very much... However, I’m no longer by myself. So please don’t cry. Or rather, I’d appreciate it if you stopped crying. I want you to always be laughing.”

“Th-That wording is cunning...” Celia was unable to speak any further, hanging her head. At the same time, Flora’s tears finally waned, while Christina silently watched their exchange with a slightly conflicted expression.

These two are truly tied by a deep bond...

It was painfully obvious that in the five years they had been idly feigning ignorance, Rio and Celia had built up a strong and trusting relationship. Thus, Christina regretted feeling guilty.

During their short journey back from Paladia, she had experienced the kindness and depth of his heart. As a consequence, she had been driven by the urge to depend on his kindness. There were times she’d almost made the wrong presumption.

However, she wasn’t allowed to make such presumptions. Christina bit down on her lip and rebuked herself.

Sir Amakawa’s kindness is directed towards Professor Celia. That’s why...

She took a deep breath, making herself the calmest person in the room.

“If I may say something?” She raised her hand to call for attention, addressing Rio and Celia.

“M-My apologies. I was immersed in the conversation.” Celia felt ashamed of how much more emotional her reaction had been than Christina’s and apologized in a fluster.

“No, I could see how strong the bond is between you. I think your relationship is lovely, which is why I’d like to make a suggestion.”

“A suggestion?”

Do you know anything? Celia looked at Rio’s face as though to say that. Rio shook his head, expressing his lack of awareness about what Christina was about to suggest.

“Back in Cleia, I invited you to join the Restoration and work in Rodania as you are now. However, I believe you should join Sir Amakawa from here onwards.”

“Me... with Rio?” Celia blinked, then looked at Rio beside her.

“Yes. Your place in the organization will remain, but you may stay wherever you wish. Whether that be here if Sir Amakawa stays in Rodania, the new mansion he received in the Galarc Kingdom, or the house Miharu and the others are living in. Of course, I’m not insisting you go out of your way to stay together with him at all times. My suggestion is for you to take more of an assistant role to Sir Amakawa.” Christina looked at the two people seated opposite her as she explained the details.

Naturally, Celia was bewildered by the sudden suggestion. “Umm, this is all so sudden. It’s a little confusing...”

“I know whatever I say will sound like I’m doing this out of self-interest, so allow me to be blunt. I want you to be the bridge connecting the Restoration to Sir Amakawa. It’s a vital role I cannot entrust to any other noble of the Restoration, so I am requesting this of you.” Christina explained her motive in a straightforward manner.

Even so, Celia hesitated in silence, unable to give an immediate reply.

“I’ve mentioned this to Sir Amakawa already, but there will be an increasing number of marriage proposals from the nobles of the Restoration from here onwards. However, by assigning Professor Celia the official position of Sir Amakawa’s assistant, we should be able to control such proposals to a much better degree,” Christina continued.

“Does that mean Celia will be a candidate for my marriage?” Rio asked.

Celia also seemed to infer that meaning and flinched in surprise.

At the same time, Flora’s eyes were also wide. Christina and Duke Huguenot had discussed the potential of Celia becoming Rio’s possible fiancée, but she hadn’t expected that topic to be brought up here and now.

“That would depend on your relationship. I won’t insist upon anything, and I won’t allow anyone else to compel you either. However, in order to stop the marriage proposals from those in the Restoration, your relationship will need to be externally perceived by others in that way.”

“Is that... Is that in order to pull Rio into the Restoration?” Celia asked shamefully, unwilling to do such a thing.

“I don’t know whether you’ll believe me, but I am personally firmly against using the relationship between you two for the benefit of the organization. Considering the treatment Sir Amakawa received from us in the past, I cannot allow such shameless behavior. However, the nobles of the Restoration are unaware of Sir Amakawa’s identity. Because of this, they will scheme to win him over. It is an axiom that doing so will bring the Restoration great benefit, after all,” Christina said with an ironic smile.

“While this may not be an appropriate metaphor, if I were to compare this to marriage, this isn’t the act of letting the Restoration-affiliated Professor Celia go to Sir Amakawa’s side, but the act of sending the Restoration-affiliated Professor Celia off to marry,” she continued, stressing her point.

“I-I see... I’m going off to marry Rio.”

The example of marriage made Celia blush faintly. From a noble’s point of view, there was a huge difference between leaving to marry into a family, and having someone else marry into yours.

“Once Professor Celia takes her position as Sir Amakawa’s assistant, she will no longer have to prioritize the Restoration’s interests. Her highest priority will be Sir Amakawa, and the Restoration will come after that. I stated just now that I want her to be the bridge connecting the Restoration to Sir Amakawa, but if conflict were to ever fall between us, she may stand on Sir Amakawa’s side and prioritize him over us,” Christina explained.

“What do you think? I plan on using the pretext of the Restoration lending its best sorcerer out as an assistant. As for what I’d like you to do for the Restoration... If you could regularly drop by to meet me, the nobles should be easier to convince.” Christina looked at Rio and Celia’s faces.

“The assistant role is just for outward appearance, right? Based on what you’ve said, having Celia become my assistant will become an excuse to stop the marriage proposals, and she’ll be considered a candidate for my marriage.”

Rio spoke of the point he was unsure about. In doing this, Celia was liable to never be married to anyone.

“Yes. This will naturally apply if we use the assistant position as a pretext to refuse marriage proposals, and even without using it as pretext, nobles will be able to infer it.”

“In that case, I cannot agree. This is a matter that concerns Celia’s life. I am capable of rejecting the marriage proposals myself.”

“I agree that this concerns her life. That’s why I’d like to leave the decision to Professor Celia. I’m not asking for an immediate reply. If this is finalized, I’ll have to report to King Francois about it too, so I’m willing to wait if the two of you need time to discuss it further.”

“Umm... No, there’s no need for that... Princess Christina, please allow me to take the role of Rio’s assistant.” Celia volunteered for the position of Rio’s assistant of her own accord. She seemed to be nervous, as she was short of breath.

“Celia...?” Rio said, staring closely at his teacher beside him.

“I-It’s fine! This is my own decision!” Celia insisted shrilly.

“But...”

“J-Just so you know, I’m not doing this for the sake of the organization. I want to return the favor I owe you, like how you wanted to do so for me. Though I probably won’t be repaying much just by becoming your assistant...”

“That’s not true...”

“Then it’s decided. If you’re worried about my marriageable years, then don’t. I told you back in the academy, I don’t intend on getting married anytime soon.”

Rio opened his mouth to say something like “you’re better off getting married,” or “you may not be able to marry for a while because of this,” but he couldn’t say anything. The words he would have perhaps uttered if he had still yet to accomplish his vengeance on Lucius didn’t come out. However, he didn’t know the reason why.

“Anyways, I don’t want to force myself into marrying someone I’m not particularly in love with. That’s why I’ll wait. I’ll wait forever. Even if I end up single for my whole life, I want to stay with you. Th-Though that might be a nuisance to you...” Celia vented her emotions towards Rio, who sat in silence.

“It isn’t a nuisance... There’s no way you’re a nuisance. It’s just, I...”

He wavered. All Rio understood right now was the fact he was unsure.

“Sir Amakawa seems to be worried... But I see that it is a very honest reaction,” Christina interrupted. “I know my suggestion was abrupt. How about we put it on hold for now?” she asked, looking at Rio and Celia’s faces.

The two of them were mindful of each other, neither agreeing nor disagreeing. Flora watched them while holding her breath. She opened her mouth to say something, but no words came out. No, perhaps she couldn’t get them out.

“In a week’s time, Sir Amakawa will be returning to Galarc’s capital. Professor Celia, I was hoping you would accompany him. Please use that time to think for yourself. I’m prepared to wait a while,” Christina said to the two of them.

“I understand. Although... I have no intention of changing my mind,” Celia calmly but resolutely asserted.

“Understood...” Rio said and nodded quietly.

◇　◇　◇

Afterwards, the group soon dispersed from their meeting.

A party was to be held tonight in celebration of Christina and Flora’s return, but Rio would only be stressed over how to treat the nobles if he attended, so Christina gave him permission to not go.

Rio and Celia proceeded to leave the consulate and headed outside. The earlier conversation lingered in the air, causing the atmosphere between them to feel a little heavy.

Suddenly, Aishia’s voice echoed within Rio and Celia’s heads.

Celia, do you want to marry Haruto?

Setting Rio aside as the contract holder, an internal path was needed in order for Aishia to send Celia telepathic messages, so she was probably dwelling within Celia’s body at the moment.

“Wha...?!” Celia squeaked, coming to a stop with a blushing face. There was no one other than Rio in the immediate vicinity, but the soldiers on guard heard her voice and noticed her.

Wait. Wh-What are you saying, Aishia?! Celia objected telepathically. Through his connection to Aishia, Rio could hear her voice as well.

Wasn’t the conversation just now about that? Aishia asked curiously.

No! I mean, kind of... But not like that! Celia must have been considerably shaken, as her objection was made in a clearly flustered voice. However, it was at this point that she realized the soldiers were watching her curiously and hastily resumed walking to avoid suspicion.

Which is it, Haruto...? Aishia asked Rio this time.

Why me? he thought, startled.

By becoming my assistant, Professor— Celia might be treated like my fiancée, he answered, feigning his composure.

Is that a bad thing?

Not exactly bad, but... Rio struggled to find an answer.

Do the two of you want to be together?

This question was probably directed at both of them.

I...would like to, Rio admitted honestly.

R-Really? Celia looked at Rio in slight surprise.

I believe it’s cowardly to remain silent about my feelings, so I’m going to convey them properly. Until now, my life has been nothing but loss. I’ve had to watch my connections continuously be taken from me. That’s why, until just recently, I only lived for my own sake... But the truth is, I haven’t just been losing things. I’ve gained more connections than what I’ve lost, Rio explained.

Rio... Celia made a face like a strong emotion was welling up within her.

I never want to lose another connection again. That’s why, if it isn’t too late, I’d like to treasure the connections I have with everyone who has treated me well. Of course, that includes you too, Celia. You’re the first connection I gained after I lost everything when I was five years old, so I want to be with you. That is what I truly feel, Rio declared.

Then you should just be together, Aishia urged.

But I know that would be selfish of me. Celia has her status as a noble to consider... I’m a coward, so I don’t want to lead Celia away from her happiness just for the sake of my desire to stay together.

In short, he didn’t have the resolution for it. Rio still didn’t have confidence in himself because he had once lost what was important to him—what he hadn’t been able to protect.

He was scared—of losing what was precious to him, of being unable to protect them. But he had already gained new cherished things...

But this was why he was anxious; he couldn’t find an answer, and his ideals were like a child’s.

He was still a coward, for now. People couldn’t change so easily.

You know, the happiest moments of my life were always when I was with you, Rio. Those times we drank tea in my research lab at the academy, and those times when we lived together in the stone house. Those were the times I forgot everything about being a noble and felt happiness, Celia said, expressing her feelings as well.

But there was also the part of me who was a noble—who thought I had to live for the sake of the kingdom. That’s why I joined the Restoration. But...

I want to stay by your side, as both an individual, and a noble. I didn’t think that was possible until now. I believed it shouldn’t be possible. But when Princess Christina suggested I become your assistant, I started wondering if it was actually possible... I was so happy, I agreed with Princess Christina before I knew it.

Celia... Rio unconsciously came to a stop and stared at Celia.

A-And so, that’s why... It’s not like I want you to take responsibility for it or anything, okay? Y-You don’t have to worry about it if other people think I’m your fiancée! Oh, but you might be worried about yourself, huh?! Celia’s face grew redder and redder, her words becoming more incoherent.

Please calm down, Rio called out to her with a wry smile.

R-Right...

I know we just left the fortress, but let’s go back to Princess Christina and tell her you’ve officially accepted the assistant role.

Okay... Celia replied hesitantly.

After that, the two of them turned around and returned to where Christina and Flora were. Their footsteps were much lighter than when they were walking away from the consulate, and they had soft smiles on their faces that spoke of the heaviness that had been lifted from their chests.

Afterword

Hello everyone—thank you for reading. This is Yuri Kitayama. As always, thank you for picking up Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles, volume 16,The Knight’s Respite.

So, how did you find volume 16?

In this volume, Rio’s revenge tale has ended and the story is transitioning to the next stage, so I tried to tie up some loose ends and lay the groundwork for the future with a bit of a breather.

Since there are people who like to read from the afterword, I’ll refrain from writing any spoilers, but in volume 16 there are people who finally meet each other, the appearance of someone new, and the feeling of everyone finally gathering together, which leaves even me, the author, feeling touched. (In my case, I leave all of the illustrations to my editor and Riv, so I’m always extremely touched when I see the wonderful art!)

From here on, there’ll be more developments between the appearing characters, the reappearance of old characters, and the resolution of various plot points that have built up until now, making the story even more interesting. Please look forward to volume 17, as it’ll only get better from here.

Speaking of volume 17, the production of the third drama CD has been decided. There’ll be over ten characters appearing in it, including popular characters from the past and new faces. Please look forward to the cast announcements! (The plot won’t affect the main story, and the contents will mostly focus on daily life during volume 17.)

I’m running out of space, so I’ll wrap things up here. I don’t normally write about my own circumstances, but perhaps once in a while... And so, I still haven’t gone on my first shrine visit of the year. I’m hoping I’ll get to go before this volume goes on sale, but I haven’t filed my taxes yet and I’m scrambling everywhere.

Things got unexpectedly busy from the end of last year, and I’m still following up on adjusting my schedule, but I’m somehow managing to continue my work in good health. Make sure you take care of yourselves too, everyone! Let’s meet again in volume 17 this summer!

Yuri Kitayama

March 2020